# TUERKE

# LARS ERICH

## **CONTACT INFO**

E-mail lars.tuerke@gmx.de

**Phone Nr** +49 151 20054738

Address Senefelderstraße 23, 10437 Berlin, Germany

**LinkedIn** www.linkedin.com/in/lars-tuerke

GitHub https://github.com/larstrk

Portfolio https://larstrk.github.io/

## **ABOUT ME**

Hey there, I'm Lars - a student, self-taught developer, and an avid climber. Currently pursuing a Master's in Industrial Engineering.

As a developer, my goal is to create a wide range of helpful applications that can make a positive impact. My journey in the world of tech began with the CS50 course from Harvard University and my work on an AI project at MTU. I'm familiar with frontend technologies like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, where I've gained basic skills and first-hand experience. I've also ventured into backend development, exploring tools like SQLite3, Flask, Python, and Git.

Beyond coding, I enjoy scaling new heights - both in my climbing adventures and my drive to tackle challenges and expand my skills.

Feel free to connect with me on LinkedIn, explore my GitHub repositories, or shoot me an email.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **WORKING STUDENT**

2022-

**MTU Maintenance** | Ludwigsfelde, Brandenburg, Germany (Process Engineering)

- Process data analysis and visualization in Tableau
- Support of an Al development project
- Process analysis and representation in MS Visio
- Working with Excel/Access VBA and KNIME
- Cost-benefit comparison and obtaining offers

INTERNSHIP 2021-2022

**MTU Maintenance** | Ludwigsfelde, Brandenburg, Germany (Production Planning and Control)

- Creation an automatic audit log for the database in Tableau
- Preparation and structuring of knowledge management in the internal wiki
- Elaboration of an overview of area and capacity planning

INTERNSHIP 2019

**IMPACT Group** | Berlin, Germany

- Recruiting employees
- Employee scheduling and HR administration

INTERNSHIP 2019

Metallbau Gottschalk GbR | Berlin, Germany

- Sawing, stamping, drilling, thread cutting, deburring
- Read and implement construction plans

# STAY ABROAD IN NEW ZEALAND

2017-2018

### **EDUCATION**

### MSc IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING

2022-

**Technical University of Berlin** | Berlin, Germany

# BEng IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING

2018-2022

**TH Wildau** | Wildau, Germany

- Thesis topic: "Introduction of an artificial intelligence in engine maintenance based on the example of the development project automatic component recognition"
- Final Grade: 2.1

ABITUR 2009-2017

**Johanna-Geissmar-Gymnasium** | Mannheim, Germany

• Final Grade: 2.1

## **SKILLS**

● ● ■ Tableau, Microsoft Office

● O Project Management, Python, Git, Confluence/Jira

O O HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQLite3, Flask, Figma

## Languages

- German (native)
- English (Full professional proficiency)